-=耐卡影音论坛=-
www.ncar.cc/bbs
欣赏更多精彩美剧
字幕源自INTERNET
911  请陈述紧急情况
9-1-1, what's your emergency?
救救我  求你了
You have to help me. Please.
我只剩几秒钟了
I only have a few seconds left.
女士  请报地址
Ma'am, what's your address?
C大街250号  求你们快点
250 Avenue C. Please hurry.
我们马上派人过去
We'll send help right away.
可以告诉我出什么事了吗
Can you tell me what's happening?
女士  我得知道发生什么事了
Ma'am, I need to know what's going on.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
女士  听得见吗
Ma'am, can you hear me?
灯灭了
The lights went out.
它来找我了
It's coming for me.
什么来找你了  女士
What's coming for you? Ma'am?
女士
Ma'am?
我要死了
I'm gonna die.
还在吗  喂
Are you there? Hello.
女士你还在吗  喂
Ma'am Are you there? Hello.
听见了吗
You hear that?
电话是被害人瓦尔·巴特勒
That call came in at 11:59
在11点59分打的
from our vic--Val Butler.
她在市区做广告主管
She's an ad exec downtown.
急救人员稍后赶到时
First responders came moments later.
沙发抵在紧锁的门上
That door was locked and that couch was in front of it.
没有强行入室的迹象
No sign of forced entry.
她看起来像是被吓死的  真正被吓死的
She looks like she's been scared to death, literally.
这是基于你渊博的医疗经验吗  卡塞尔先生
Is that based on your vast medical experience, Mr. Castle?
不  基于她看起来
No, based on the fact
其作品多以死亡为主题
像是爱德华·蒙克的画
She looks like an Edvard Munch painting.
真够吓人的
Really freaky.
死因是什么
So what was the cause of death?
没有外部伤痕
Well, there's no external trauma,
没有刺伤类伤痕
no puncture or stab wounds.
给她进行尸检后
Once I get her on the slab,
我会对死因及凶手有进一步的了解
I'll know more about how she died and who did it.
得是个人才行
If it was a who.
什么意思
Meaning?
她说的是"它来找我了"
Meaning she said "It's coming for me."
不是他或她  而是它
Not "He" or "She," but "It."
你们瞧她都在看什么
Look at what she was researching here--
《如何辟邪》
"How To Keep Away Evil,"
《如何抵挡恶灵》
"How To Ward Off Evil Spirits,"
都市传说的书
A book on urban legends.
门那边  挂着马蹄
Over by the door, horseshoes.
还有两个印第安风铃
I've clocked two indian wind chimes,
这里和那里
There and there.
这些是用来抵挡恶灵的
These are things used to ward off evil spirits,
比如说帕穆特医生
like Perlmutter.
我听到了
I heard that.
你什么意思  卡塞尔
What are you saying, Castle?
是恶灵要了她的命吗
Oh, was the boogeyman out to get her?
我是说也许这是她的想法
I'm saying maybe that's what she thought--
所以才会说  "它来找我了"
Why she said "It's coming for me,"
所以灯灭了
why the lights went out,
她又死得这么离奇
why she inexplicably died,
而且看起来很害怕
and why she looks so scared.
她害怕是因为她要被杀害了
She was scared because she was about to be killed
凶手是个人
by an actual person.
所以我们该努力找出这个人
So we should spend our time looking for that person.
大家开始排查  在楼内逐一问话
Let's set up a canvass and talk to everyone in the building
看有谁听到或看到什么
that might have seen or heard something.
瓦尔出什么事了
Wh-what happened to Val?
到底怎么回事
What's going on?
我晚上在大学做研究助理
I work nights as a research assistant at the college.
我昨晚应该留在家里的
But I should've stayed home last night.
我知道她碰到麻烦了
I knew something was up with her.
什么意思
What do you mean?
过去几天她非常奇怪
She's been weird the past couple of days.
不吃不睡
She hadn't been eating or sleeping.
总是疑神疑鬼的  总是锁上门
She was really paranoid, always locking the doors.
她说了是什么问题吗
Did she say what was wrong?
我问了
I asked,
但她说她不想谈
but she said she didn't want to talk about it.
阿曼达  你知不知道
Amanda, do you know of anyone
是否有人想伤害她
that would've wanted to hurt her?
她的前男友
Her ex-boyfriend.
前男友叫弗雷迪·贝克
Boyfriend's name is Freddie Baker,
31岁
31.
案底相当精彩  拒捕
Quite the resume-- resisting arrest,
人身攻击
assault and battery.
听起来像是白马王子
Sounds like a prince.
不过瓦尔变聪明了
Yeah, Val wised up, though.
分手后  她申请了法院限制令
She filed a restraining order against him after they broke up.
埃斯波西托在查他昨晚在哪里
Esposito is checking into where he was last night.
瓦尔的家人和朋友那边有什么消息
So what did we get from Val's family and friends?
他们过去三天都没联络上她
Just that they hadn't heard from her in the last three days.
她不回任何信息
She wasn't returning their messages.
三天  瓦尔的室友说她
Three days--that's how long Val's roommate
正是三天前开始变奇怪的
said she'd been acting strangely.
我调查了她人生的最后72小时
Yeah, so I dug into the last 72 hours of her life.
除了用信用卡支付
Besides a credit card charge
去格林威治的火车票
for a train ticket to Greenwich,
没其它不寻常的
there was nothing else unusual.
她去格林威治做什么
What was she doing in Greenwich?
这我还在查
I'm still looking into that,
但过去几天的反常情况
but as far as abnormalities for the last few days,
就这些了
that was it.
不  还有  风铃
Uh, no, there's more. The wind chime,
马蹄  都市传说的书
the horse shoe, the book on urban legends--
都是两天前网上购买的
All bought online two days ago.
仿佛是瓦尔认为
Almost as if Val thought
某种恶灵找上她了
some kind of evil spirit was coming for her.
卡塞尔  她觉得会发生的
Castle, what she thought was gonna happen
与事实发生的
versus what actually happened
完全是两码事
are two completely different things.
对  如果说瓦尔有什么麻烦
Yeah, because if Val was a victim of anything,
就是她挑男人的眼光太差
it's her lousy taste in men.
排查有结果
Canvass popped.
有个邻居见到弗雷迪在她死前一小时
One of her neighbors saw Freddie in the building
出现在公寓大楼
an hour before her death.
我绝不会伤害瓦尔的
I would never hurt Val.
我爱她
I loved her.
真的吗  那你如何解释她申请的针对你的
Really? Then how do you explain this restraining order
法院限制令
that she filed against you?
这是情书吗
Was that a love letter?
这是误会
A misunderstanding.
我们有目击证人看到你
Well, we got a witness that saw you
昨晚去了瓦尔的公寓  弗雷迪
in Val's apartment last night, Freddie.
但我没有杀她
But I didn't kill her.
没错  我去了
Yes, I went over there,
但那是因为她求我去的
but only because she begged me to.
你觉得我们会相信
Do you actually expect us to believe
她在申请法院限制令后
that she invited you over to her apartment
还会邀请你过去吗
after she filed a restraining order?
真的  她说她想复合
It's true. She said she wanted to get back together.
但我去了后  她只是
But when I got there, all she did was
指责我给她寄了什么包裹
accuse me of sending her some package.
什么包裹
What package?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
但当我说我什么都没寄过时
But when I told her I didn't send her anything,
她就开始慌了
she started freaking out.
什么意思
How was she freaking out?
她不停念叨  "这是真的"
She kept saying, "It's real".
什么是真的
What's real?
不知道
I don't know.
她的话  完全语无伦次
She wasn't making... any sense.
她不断问我
She kept asking me
是否相信恶魔的力量
if I believed in the power of evil.
我不想因为违反限制令惹祸上身
I didn't want to get in trouble for breaking the R.O.,
就离开她家  跟朋友出去了
so I got out of there, went to hang out with friends.
但我离开她家的时候
But when I left that apartment,
瓦尔绝对还活着
Val was alive.
我发誓
I swear.
弗雷迪的不在场证明核实了
Freddie's alibi checks out.
他的朋友证实他11点与他们碰面
Friends confirm that he met them at 11:00.
他们在一家夜店玩到天亮
They hung out at a club till dawn.
那么他不是凶手了
So he's not our guy.
我只想提醒你们  瓦尔问他
Well, I'll just point out that Val asked him
是否相信恶魔的力量
if he believed in the power of evil
还不断说什么是真的
and then was talking about how it was "real".
-我不愿这么说...  -那就别说
- I hate to say it-- - Then don't.
鉴证组在她公寓里发现包裹了吗
Did C.S.U. find a package at her apartment?
没  但他们光顾着找凶案证物没查邮件
No, but they were looking for evidence of the murder not mail.
也许那才是让她惊慌的东西
So maybe that's what freaked Val out.
她知道寄包裹的人想要杀她
She knew that that package was coming from her killer.
有什么发现吗
Did you find anything yet?
有  柜子里的细高跟鞋比你的还多
Yes, a closet with more stilettos than yours.
我以为你的鞋量已无人能及了
Didn't think it was possible.
你呢  有发现吗
How about you? Any luck?
有  似乎她收到的包裹
Uh, yes. Looks like the package she got
里面有一张CD或DVD
contained a CD or a DVD
所以留心找找光碟
so be on the lookout for a disc.
光碟  明白了
Disc, got ya.
救我
Help me.
贝克特
Uh, Beckett?
Beckett?
你能过来一下吗
Can you come here?
你看过了
You saw!
第三天的午夜
Midnight on the third day...
就是你的死期
you die!
你还好吧  你找到什么了吗
Are you okay? Did you find something?
你说瓦尔是哪天收到包裹的
When did you say Val got that package?
遇害前三天
Three days before she died.
正是第三天的午夜
That was midnight on the third day.
她是因为看这光碟而死
She died because she saw this disc.
现在我也看了
And now I saw it,
下一个就是我了
which means I'm next.
灵
书
妙
探
灵
书
妙
探
第五季 第十七集
据传有一段神秘的录像
"Legend tells of a mysterious video
能够控制冥界恶魔的力量
"that can harness the forces of evil from the beyond.
这张碟预示着巨大的不幸
"The disc is a harbinger of great misfortune,
标记它的观看者
"marking its watchers
并让他们无法逃脱死亡的下场
and sentencing them to certain and unavoidable death."
我跟瓦尔一样看到了光碟
I saw it, just like Val did.
所以她才会说  "它来找我了"
That's why she said "It's coming for me".
所以她知道自己何时会死
That's how she knew when she was gonna die,
并竭尽全力阻挡恶灵
why she was trying to ward off spirits--
都是因为看到了光碟上的讯息
because of the message on that disc.
一张DVD要怎么杀人
How's a DVD gonna kill you?
它会像超级忍者那样  砍下你的脑袋吗
Is it gonna come at you like a ninja star, cut your head off?
碟片本身不会置你于死地  埃斯波西托
The actual DVD will not kill me, Esposito.
是里面的灵魂
It will be the spirit inside the DVD,
就像《午夜凶铃》里那样
just like in "The Ring".
就是  是那个...
Ooh, ooh, the one...
全身湿透了的诡异的小女孩
with the creepy waterlogged little girl
从电视机里爬出来的那部
who crawls out of the TV.
看过那片子后我好些天没睡
I didn't sleep for days after that movie.
没错  谢谢  那电影
Yes, exactly. Thank you. That movie.
是编出来的
It's fiction.
是讲都市传说的书上的一个恐怖故事
It's a horror story in a book about urban legends.
对  我是说  因为
Yeah, I mean, because...
仅此而已  对不对
that's all it is, right?
只是个传说
A legend.
很多传说都来源于现实
Many legends are based in truth.
我看了录像
I saw the video.
三天后的午夜  我就会死
At midnight in three days time, I will die.
卡塞尔  那讯息不是留给你的
Oh, Castle, that message wasn't for you.
是给瓦尔的恐吓  并非来自灵魂
It was a threat for Val. And it wasn't made by spirits.
而是来自杀害她的凶手
It was made by her murderer.
那么追踪到寄光碟的人
So tracing the disc to whoever sent it
就能找到凶手了
should lead us straight to him.
-埃斯波  -是
- Espo. - Yeah.
这个空运单上有个信箱  你能查查吗
There's a P.O. box on this airbill. Could you look into it?
-行  -还有  莱恩
- Yeah. - And, Ryan, why don't you
你也来看看这光碟  看...
take a look at this disc and see--
抱歉  什么
Oh, I'm--I'm sorry, what?
你也这样  兄弟
Et tu, bro?
你不是说这个故事就是个传说吗
What did you say about the story being a legend?
没错  但
Um, well, uh,
珍妮和我
Jenny and I,
我们在努力造人
we are trying to make a baby,
所以书上写的所有迷信我们都得信
so we're abiding by every superstition in the book.
好吧  那你来  埃斯波
Okay. Fine. Here, Espo.
不  我不  我不能
Oh, nah. I c-- I can't--
我不能看那个
I can't watch that.
要是我看了这个  就显得我的搭档
If I watch that, it's gonna make my partner out
是胆小鬼
to be a wimp,
我不能这样
and I can't have that.
-多谢  兄弟  -没事
- Thanks, bro. - Yeah.
我真为你俩悲哀
This is so pathetic.
好吧  我看就是了
Fine. I will watch it.
等等  你这是干什么
Wait. No. What are you doing?
卡塞尔  我在做我的本职工作
Castle, I'm doing my job.
这里总得有人干吧
Someone here has to.
想想可能的后果
Okay, think of the risks.
你也许不信这些
You may not think there's anything to this,
但万一你错了呢
but what if you're wrong?
我很感谢你的关心
You know, I appreciate your concern,
但这不过是张光碟罢了
but it's just a DVD.
不  你不能就这么播
You--you don't-- you can't just play it.
让我做点预防措施
Let me take precautions here.
不能让整个分局的人都跟我一起遭殃
Don't want the whole precinct suffering my fate.
好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay.
你想握着我的手吗
You want to hold my hand?
卡塞尔  我一点不害怕
Castle, I'm not scared.
可是我害怕呀
Well, I wasn't asking for you.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
有差别吗
Does it matter?
救我
Help me.
那是什么声音
What are those sounds?
我说吧  后面的更糟
Right? It gets worse.
马上就到了
Wait for it.
你看过了
You saw!
三天后的午夜
Midnight on the third day...
就是你的死期
You die!
没错  是有点恐怖
You're right. It is kinda creepy.
谢谢
Thank you.
因为凶手故意做的很恐怖  卡塞尔
Because the killer made it creepy, Castle.
也许死者曾见过这些画面
Maybe these images meant something to the victim,
或许能查出她和凶手的关系
clues to the relationship between her and the killer.
等等
Wait.
倒回去
Go back.
那个  那个  那是...
That one--that one there. That's the, um...
那是西藏轮  象征着重生
That's the tibetan wheel. Symbolizes rebirth.
等下
Hang on.
那是个共济会罗盘  那是...
That is the masonic compass. That's...
那代表了复活
They felt it represented, uh, resurrection.
你想说什么
Your point being?
重生  复活
Rebirth? Resurrection?
这段录像显然复活了某个死去的东西
This video obviously resurrects something from the great beyond,
危险的东西
something dangerous,
会杀人的东西
something... murderous.
还能有什么别的解释呢
I mean, what other explanation can there be?
有很多解释  卡塞尔
There are plenty of explanations, Castle,
而且都与超自然现象无关
and none of them are supernatural.
实际上  我敢说帕穆特已经查明死因了
In fact, I bet Perlmutter has our cause of death by now.
毒检尸检报告都应该出来了
Those tox and autopsy reports should be done.
贝克特探长
Ah, Detective Beckett
还有讨厌鬼卡塞尔
and defective Castle.
帕穆特  瓦尔·巴特勒是怎么死的
So, Perlmutter, how was Val Butler killed?
死于心力衰竭
It appears she died of heart failure.
27岁吗
At 27?
她有心脏疾病吗
Did she have heart problems?
心脏停跳绝对是个毛病
Well, she certainly did once it stopped beating.
为什么会停跳
What made it stop?
有没有可能是中毒
Is it possible that she was poisoned
或是吸毒过量
or O.D.'ed on drugs?
血检没有异常
Nothing showed up on her blood panels.
那是什么导致她...
What about what caused her, um...
死后面部肌肉收缩
Well, postmortem contractions of the facial muscles
也并不是前所未闻
are not unheard of.
你不知道死因是什么
You don't know what killed her.
-不能这么说  -你有想法了吗
- I wouldn't say that. - Do you have a theory?
现在还没
Not at the present time.
那就是说你不知道
That means you don't know.
唯一的解释
And the only explanation
就是瓦尔看到了极其吓人的东西
is that Val faced something so scary,
于是心脏停跳
it stopped her heart
脸也僵在最后的表情上  就是惊恐
and froze her face in the last expression she had, terror.
承认吧
Admit it.
卡塞尔先生  我只能说  到目前为止
All I'll say, Mr. Castle, is that for now,
死因未知
cause of death is unknown.
未知
Unknown?
听见了吗
Hear that?
不妙啊
Not good.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
看我的遗愿清单
Checking my bucket list
看两天内我能实现几条
to see how many things I can get done in two days.
你们有谁能把我介绍给比尔·夏特纳吗
Can either one of you introduce me to Bill Shatner?
即威廉·夏特纳  《星际迷航》的柯克舰长
查明是谁寄了这张光盘
You know, finding who sent this disc
应该能让卡塞尔好受一点
should make Castle feel a whole lot better.
是啊  但如果真被卡塞尔说中
Yeah, but what if the worst happens
发生了最糟的情况呢
and--and Castle's right?
你觉得他会在遗嘱里提到我吗
Do you think he put me in his will?
老兄  一点都不好玩
Dude, uncool.
怎么了
What?
我就是好奇
I'm just wondering.
卡塞尔要是死了是挺难过的
I mean, Castle's death would be sad and all,
但他的法拉利绝对能减轻我的悲痛
but his Ferrari sure would lessen my grief.
你知道光说这种话也会遭报应吧
You do realize that even putting that out in the universe is bad karma?
拜托  卡塞尔不会死的
Please. Castle's not gonna die.
我们要抓的也不是恶灵
We're not dealing with an evil spirit.
我们要抓的是有寄件人地址的人
We're dealing with a guy who has a return address.
邮政服务
为什么大家都来问1135号邮箱呢
Why does everybody keep asking about box 1135?
等下  还有谁问了
Wait. Who else has been asking about it?
有个褐发的女人几天前来过
Some brunette chick came in here a couple days ago.
大概是瓦尔
Probably Val.
你怎么跟她说的
What did you tell her?
什么都没说
Nothing, bruh.
有违公司规定
It's against company policy.
我觉得这个胜过公司规定
Well, I think that this trumps company policy.
邮箱是谁的
So who owns the box?
这就是奇怪的地方了
Ah, that's the weird thing.
邮箱的主人大概在三个月前死了
The guy who owns it died, like, three months ago.
所以他不可能寄包裹
So he couldn't have sent that package
除非他是从冥府寄的
unless he sent it from the great beyond.
邮箱最后的租客是安德鲁·莱维
The box was last rented by an Andrew Levine,
他三个月前死于肝功能衰竭
who died of liver failure three months ago.
不过我觉得他和案件无关
Somehow I don't think he's connected to this case.
那么凶手掩盖了踪迹
So the killer covered his tracks.
他一定是在寄件单上随便写了一个邮箱号
He must have written a random P.O. box on the packaging slip.
-或者  -不  莱恩  没有或者
- Or-- - No. Ryan, there is no "Or."
我只是说  也许我们追查不到
I'm just saying, maybe the reason
包裹源头的原因
we can't trace this package's origin
是因为它是从另一个世界寄来的
is because it was sent from another realm.
莱恩说得对  是从另一个世界寄来的
Ryan's right. It was sent from another realm.
新泽西
New Jersey.
我查了瓦尔包裹的空运单号
I looked into the airbill number on Val's package.
发现是同一个人寄出的
Turns out it's one in a sequence of airbills
几张空运单中的一个
all sent from the same guy--
寄件人杰森·本内特
Jason Bennett.
他住在霍博肯
He lives in Hoboken.
纽约警局
NYPD!
兄弟  我想告诉你
Hey, bro. I just want you to know...
我觉得你应该知道
I just thought you should know
我很珍视我们的友谊
that I really value our friendship.
好吧  谢了
Okay. Thanks.
对我来说是无价的
It's priceless to me.
很好
Great.
如果我们能给它定个价  你觉得是多少
But if we could put a price on it, what would that be?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我只想知道我们的友谊值多少
I just want to know how much our friendship would be worth
如果你...
if you were--
死了
Dead!
我们来晚了
We got to Bennett too late.
对  晚了差不多两天
Yeah, uh, about two days too late.
看起来他死了有两天了
That looks like about how long he's been dead.
他不可能杀死瓦尔
He couldn't have killed Val.
而他四天前
And he got a package
和瓦尔一样收到了装有光盘的包裹
with a disc in it just like Val, four days ago.
这里也断电了
There was a blackout here, too.
同样的作案手法  同样吓人的尸体
Same M.O., same freaky-ass body.
第三个午夜
The third day at midnight.
我就知道不该让你看那光盘
I knew I shouldn't have let you watch that disc.
现在不到48小时
Now in 48 hours...
我们俩都会死
We'll both be dead.
时间轴：三水  裙带菜
校对：大卫熊  请叫我草海柱    后期&监制：瓜瓜
鉴证组在杰森家发现了一堆空运单
C.S.U. just found a stack of airbills at Jason's place.
这么说  杀手用了其中一个
So then the killer used one of them
寄光碟给瓦尔
to send the disc to Val.
或许我们该复制一份光盘
Maybe we should make a copy of the DVD
寄给别人
and send it to someone else.
这是《午夜凶铃》里救人的方式
That's how they saved people in "The Ring."
对  可收到拷贝的人都死了
Yeah, but all those people who got a copy died.
是啊  你那是把皮球踢给别人
Yeah, you'd just be passing the buck off to someone else.
很冷血  兄弟
That's cold, bro.
好吧  谁有高见
Okay, does anyone have a better solution?
我们没有对策了
Because we need one,
就算不为我  也为贝克特着想吧
if not for me, at least for Beckett.
卡塞尔  你真好  你宁可把生的希望留给我
Castle, that's so sweet. You want me to outlive you?
当然了
Of course.
不然谁为我的无私和牺牲精神歌功颂德
Who else is gonna tell my tale of sacrifice and selflessness?
好了  我们不必给任何人歌功颂德
Okay, we won't be telling anyone anything.
我们都不会有事
We're both gonna be fine.
都有两个看过光碟的人死了
How can you say that when we have not one
你怎么还能说这话
but two dead DVD watchers?
这两名死者除了那张光碟
There's gotta be a better connection
一定还有更合理的联系
between our two victims than that disc.
莱恩  去问下杰森的家人
Ryan, can you check in with Jason's family,
看有没有人认识瓦尔
see if anyone recognizes Val?
好  这就去
Yeah. On it.
埃斯波西托  你不如去对照一下他们的档案
Espo, why don't you cross-reference their records
看他们俩之间是否有相似点
and see if there are any similarities between the two of them?
如果我们俩的照片要贴在那板上
You know, if there's gonna be pictures of us hanging up there,
我们现在就该选照片了
we should really pick 'em out now.
卡塞尔
You know, Castle...
我们可以用那张
We could always use the photo
我前几天给你拍的床照
that I took of you in bed the other night.
我不确定我想给大家留下那种印象
I don't know if that's how I want to be remembered.
卡塞尔  我开玩笑的
Castle, I was joking.
我们的照片不会贴在那块板上
There will be no photos of us on that murder board.
到明天  我们会找到
By tomorrow, we are gonna find a connection
这两名死者的联系
between our two victims
直接引导我们找到真实存在的凶手
that will leads us straight to a flesh-and-blood killer.
与此同时
In the meantime...
现在不早了  好吗
It's getting kinda late, okay?
我们就查到这里吧
So why don't we just call it a night?
知道吗  其实
You know what? Actually...
我们今晚可以回我家
We could go back to my place tonight
多拍点照片
and take some more photos.
我可能相信
Well, I might be convin--
等等
Whoa. Wait a minute.
我看过的每部恐怖片里
In every horror movie I've ever seen...
做爱几乎保证了
Having sex pretty much guarantees
我们会死
we will die.
所以为了我们俩的安全
So... for the safety of us both,
我们先忍忍吧
I say we just hold off.
你确定
Are you sure?
你想想  卡塞尔
I mean, think about it, Castle.
这可能是我们最后一次
This could be our last time.
没关系
That's--okay...
你现在做的事
What you're doing right now,
是帮倒忙  而且...
this is not helping. This--
我要走了  远离诱惑
I'm gonna... remove myself from temptation.
好好睡一晚我就能想出好点子了
A good night's sleep will give me some perspective.
我  这...
I--this is...
喂
Hello.
韦斯[《惊声尖叫》导演]  我是里奇
Wes. Hey, it's Rick.
天呐  里奇  这大半夜的
Jeez, Rick. It's after midnight.
我知道  抱歉  我需要点建议
Yeah, sorry. I just, um, I need some advice.
打扑克又输给史蒂芬·金了
Is Stephen King beating you at Texas hold'em again?
美著名恐怖小说家
怎么可能
Yeah, right.
不是  其实是关于你的电影
No, but, um, this is actually about your movies.
韦斯·克雷文就是恐怖的代名词
I mean, the name Wes Craven is synonymous with horror.
美国恐怖教父
你靠把大家吓得屁滚尿流赚得盆满钵满
You've made a fortune scaring the crap out of people.
《夺魂盛筵》
"My Soul To Take,"
《猛鬼街》系列
All the "Nightmare On Elm Streets,"
恐怖至极
terrifying.
你半夜给我打电话
So you called me up in the middle of the night
是为了加入我的粉丝会吗
to join my fan club, what?
当然不是
Ha ha. No.
我知道你为你所有影片中
I know that you've researched evil spirits
来自地府的幽灵都做过调查
who reach out from the beyond for all your films.
当然
Of course.
我只是好奇你是否知道
I was just wondering if you knew
怎样抵挡这些讨厌鬼
how to stop those pesky suckers.
你是要制作自己的电影吗
Is this you making your own movie?
你在写恐怖片剧本吗
I mean, are you writing a horror screenplay?
对
Yes.
我只是想跟你良性竞争一下
I just thought I'd give you a little friendly competition.
只是遇到了瓶颈
Just got a little writer's block is all.
好吧  什么故事
Okay, what's the story?
粗犷英俊的男主角
Um... ruggedly handsome hero
和他十分不讲迷信的女友
and his notoriously practical lady friend
看了张据说会在三天内杀死观看者的光碟
watch a disc that's killing its viewers within three days.
是吗  你不觉得这缺乏创意吗
Really? You don't think that's a little derivative?
是的  可我希望结局别出心裁
Yes, but I am hoping to distinguish the ending,
故事最后  主角都活了下来
You know, make the third act a, um, survival tale
而不是全都死光
rather than a bloodbath.
我只是想不出
I just can't... figure out
怎么让主角脱离危险
how to get my heroes out of this mess.
关键总是在于鬼怪的原始故事
So the key is always in the spirit's origin story.
一旦你找到出处
Once you have that,
就能开始找出鬼怪的弱点
you can start to figure out the spirit's weaknesses.
如果它使用光碟作为进入我们世界的大门
If it's using the disc as its portal into our world...
那光碟也会包含种种
Then the disc would contain clues
鬼怪故事的线索
as to the spirit's story.
韦斯  谢谢
Wes, thank you.
谢谢  听着  哥们  很晚了  我得挂了
Thank you. Listen, buddy, it's late. I gotta go.
良性竞争个鬼啊
Friendly competition, my ass.
你们一定在开玩笑
You guys have gotta be kidding me.
没发现这两个死者的任何关联
We didn't find a single connection between our victims?
没  这两个人风马牛不相干
No, the two were as different as night and day.
杰森是个退休军医
Jason was a retired ex-army doc.
瓦尔是个年轻的曼哈顿广告主管
Val was a young Manhattan ad exec.
瓦尔生在佛罗里达  杰森在爱荷华长大
Val was born in Florida. Jason grew up in Iowa.
他们没共同朋友  也没亲属关系
They didn't share any friends and they weren't family.
杰森的亲人都认不出瓦尔的照片
And none of Jason's relatives recognized Val's photo?
对  而且瓦尔的家人
No, and nobody from Val's family
也都没见过或听过杰森
had ever seen or heard of Jason.
我们还在细查他们的档案
We're still looking through their records,
可目前一无所获
but so far, nothing.
那我们走到死胡同了
So we're at a dead end?
未必
Ah, maybe not.
我想了又想
After much reflection,
发现问题关键在于
I realized the key to solving this
弄清光盘上的故事
is figuring out the story on the DVD.
为了这个目的
To that end,
我把一副图像发给了我的"信众"  集思广益
I crowdsourced one of the images to my legion of followers.
有人认出来了吗
And someone recognized it?
那还用说
Oh, you betcha.
据炫猫39称
According to be dazzle cats 39,
这就是布伦瑞克旅馆
You're looking at the Brunswick Inn
在坎贝尔港
in port campbell.
说对了
Bingo.
瓦尔的信用卡记录显示她于2008年11月
Val's credit card records show that she spent a few nights
在布伦瑞克旅馆住过几晚
at the Brunswick Inn in november 2008.
貌似杰森也在那儿住过
And it looks like Jason crashed there, too,
也是在2008年11月
also in november 2008.
那么两名死者在同一段时间
Okay, so both of our victims stayed at that inn
都在那个旅馆
at the same time.
也许他们俩有一腿
So maybe they were having an affair.
2008年的时候  瓦尔24岁
Well, in 2008, Val would've been 24.
杰森66岁  有一腿的话...
Jason would've been 66. An affair would've been--
-恶心  -我刚想说不太可能
- Gross. - I was gonna say unlikely.
看起来不像是有一腿
It doesn't look like an affair.
他们没住同一间房
They stayed in separate rooms.
两名死者当时都在旅馆
Well, the victims were at the inn.
旅馆又出现在碟片上  中间肯定有联系
The inn was on the disc. There's gotta be a connection.
旅馆肯定发生了
The inn must be the place
可怖的闹鬼事件
where some unspeakable horror befell the spirits.
想想吧
Think about it.
《午夜凶铃》《惊魂记》《闪灵》
"The Ring," "Psycho," "The Shining"--
恐怖的旧旅馆
It's when we get to the creepy old motel
是一切灵异故事的开始
that everything starts really going south.
这里肯定是鬼故事的始发地
So this must the location of the spirit's origin story.
或者瓦尔和杰森在那个旅馆
Or somehow Val and Jason connected with
与人类杀手产生了某种联系
the human killer at that inn.
我的版本更好
My version's better.
你们去查一下布伦瑞克旅馆
Why don't you look into the Brunswick Inn?
看看有什么危险信号  过往罪案
See if there any red flags, past crimes.
我和卡塞尔去坎贝尔港
Castle and I will go to Port Campbell
看能找到什么线索
and see what we can find.
或许我应该  留在这里
Maybe I should... stay here.
我是说
I mean,
旅馆只是谜题的一部分
The inn is just one piece of the puzzle.
我要查查视频里的其它影像
I should really check the other images on the video,
看能找到什么线索
see what I can figure out.
你自愿再看一遍视频吗
Whoa. You're volunteering to watch that thing again?
是啊  反正我只能死一次
Yeah. Not like I can get any deader.
布伦瑞克旅馆
有人吗
Hello.
看来这里没人
It doesn't look like there's anyone here.
至少在这个世纪  没人来过
Doesn't look like anyone's been here this century.
你不相信卡塞尔那套荒谬的鬼魂理论吧
You're not buying into Castle's spirit craziness,are you?
当然不信
No.
你以为我会怕那些老套的篝火故事吗
You think I'm afraid of some old campfire story?
-我不是小孩子了  -需要帮忙吗
- I'm a grown-ass man. - Need help?
我解释下
Just so you know,
我只是被吓了一下  不是害怕
Um, that was me being startled, not scared.
旅馆是你开的吗
You run this place?
开了41年了  但你们来得不巧
41 years now, but you're in the wrong place.
我们旅馆这季不开放
We're closed for the season.
我们就问你几个问题
We just need to ask you a few questions.
你认得这两个人吗
Uh, do you recognize these people?
瓦尔·巴特勒和杰森·本内特  他们
Val Butler and Jason Bennett-- they--
他们2008年曾留宿在这里
they stayed here back in 2008.
2008年  好久了  来来往往很多人
Long time ago, 2008. Seen a lot of faces come and go.
他们是11月住在这里的
They would've been here in november.
你记得那段时间有什么不寻常的事吗
Do you remember anything unusual from that period?
你们知道他们的房号吗
You wouldn't happen to know their room numbers.
知道  213和313
Yeah, uh, 213 and 313.
13号房间  那些房间  不是...
THE 13s. Those rooms, they're not...
一般的房间
normal rooms.
当时留给了法院庭审的涉案人员
They're reserved for people involved in trials at the courthouse,
在1135号区
down at 1135 elm.
1135  跟包裹上的邮政信箱号码一致
1135, that's the same number as the P.O. Box on that package.
那就是了
That's gotta be it, then.
凶手肯定跟08年在法院的庭审
The murders have to be connected to a trial
有一些联系
held at the courthouse in november of '08.
08年11月只审了一个案子
There was only one trial took place in november '08.
那是个可怕的案子
It was a terrible thing.
你还记得五年前的庭审吗
You remember a trial from five years ago?
谁都忘不了
No one here can forget.
那可是世纪审判
It was the trial of the century.
那人杀了六个人
That man murdered half a dozen people.
你说的是谁
Who are you talking about?
奈杰尔·马利瑞
Nigel Malloy.
那个连环杀手
The serial killer?
一切都和奈杰尔·马利瑞有关
This is all about Nigel Malloy.
这下都说得通了
It makes perfect sense.
光盘里的钟楼
The clock tower from the DVD
与他受审法院的钟楼是一样的
it's the same clock tower from the courthouse where he was tried.
屋顶和小巷
The rooftop and the alley
是第三第四起凶案的犯罪现场
were the scenes of his third and fourth murders.
然后杰森和瓦尔
Yeah, and Jason and Val--
都是08连环凶杀案的目击证人
both witnesses in his 2008 murder trial.
那么奈杰尔·马利瑞一定会报复
Okay, so somehow Nigel Malloy must be taking revenge
指证他的人
against the people that testified against him.
但是有一个问题
Uh, yeah, there's only one problem.
奈杰尔·马利瑞已经死了
Nigel Malloy is dead.
三年前死于狱中
He died in prison three years ago.
奈杰尔·马利瑞  人称"死神"
Nigel Malloy -- they called him "The Grim Reaper. "
他的标志性手段是
His signature--
就像我们在视频里看到的灼伤标记
searing symbols like the ones we saw in the video
直接烫在死者的皮肉上
into the flesh of his victims.
原来瓦尔和杰森目击了
Turns out that Val and Jason were witnesses
马利瑞绑架第一起命案的死者艾瑟尔·阿隆佐
to the kidnapping of Malloy's first victim -- Esther Alonzo.
他把她从新泽西的游乐园绑架过来
He abducted her from an amusement park in New Jersey.
在地下室里折磨了几天才杀死她
tortured her in his basement for days before killing her.
他让当地警方忙得团团转
He had the local police running around in circles.
他们甚至还抓错了人
They even arrested the wrong guy
在他杀了五个人之后才抓到
before capturing him five bodies later.
考虑到他死在狱中
Well, considering he died in prison,
我得说他在这两起凶案的不在场证明成立了
I'd say he has a pretty good alibi for our two murders.
凶手另有其人
It's gotta be someone else.
别那么肯定
Don't be so sure.
看看他死前接受采访时
Take a look at what Nigel Malloy said in an interview he did...
说的话
right before he died.
马利瑞先生
So, Mr. Malloy,
你说你相信自己不会死吗
are you saying you actually believe you can't die?
我杀死的人让我深刻洞悉了死亡
My victims gave me unique insight into death,
死亡的秘密
into its secrets.
即使我的肉身毁灭了  灵魂会延续
Even when my body perishes, my essence will continue on.
我会一直活下去
I will continue on.
你看
You see...
死亡仅仅是开始
death is just the beginning.
他为"精神病患者"[惊魂记直译]注入了新含义
That guy gives a whole new meaning to the word "Psycho. "
如果他真的找到了延续灵魂的方法呢
What if he did... find a way to let his spirit live on?
就像那些惊悚片里的杀手
Like the killer in those chucky movies
把灵魂注入傀儡
who transferred his spirit into that spooky doll.
正是如此  只不过这次不是傀儡  是光盘
Exactly, only instead of a doll, It's a DVD.
这就解释了"见者死"的预言
That explains the message "You saw, you die. "
目击者看了到他作案所以必须死
The witnesses saw his crimes so they must die.
按照这个逻辑  我们都不会死
Well, then given that logic, we'd both be okay
因为我们不是目击证人
because we're not witnesses.
但你是个警察  我是个警察  助手
But you're a cop. I'm a cop... helper.
我是说  你不觉得一个被判刑的连环杀手
I mean, you don't think a convicted serial killer
会对纽约警局心怀怨恨吗
is gonna have an ax to grind with the NYPD?
卡塞尔  这事跟奈杰尔·马利瑞无关
Castle,  Nigel Malloy is not involved.
他已经死了
He's dead.
但或许有别人代替他作案
But someone else might be acting on his behalf.
莱恩  跟坎贝尔港的地区检察官谈谈
Ryan, talk to the D. A. in port campbell.
找到其他那些目击证人  并确保他们的安全
Let's locate those other witnesses and make sure they're safe.
-好的  -法庭记录都被封存了
- Yeah. - The court records were sealed.
凶手怎么知道目击证人有哪些
How would the killer know who the witnesses were?
等一下
Uh, w-wait a minute.
奈杰尔·马利瑞有个弟弟  叫里奥普
Nigel Malloy had a brother. Leopol
地区检察官曾指控他协助处理尸体
The D. A. accused him of helping dispose of the bodies.
是的  辩护人说过
Yes,  the defense said...
奈杰尔的弟弟对他言听计从
that Nigel had an almost hypnotic hold over his brother.
他因为精神错乱被判无罪
He was found not guilty by reason of insanity,
之后被送去了精神病院
and they shipped him off to an asylum.
-他还在里面吗  -我查一下
- Is he still there? - I am checking.
等等  这可有意思了
Wait. This is interesting.
什么
What?
他进的那家精神病院  在格林威治村
The asylum that they sent him to,  It's in Greenwich.
瓦尔拿到DVD那天就是去了那里
That's where Val went the day she got the DVD.
她是去见里奥普·马利瑞了
She went to see Leopold Malloy.
是的  那位年轻小姐几天前确实来过
Yes, that young lady did stop by a few days ago.
你知道他们谈了什么
Do you have any idea what they might have talked about
或者他对她说了什么话吗
or what he might have said to her?
我恐怕无从知晓  亲爱的
I'm afraid not, dear.
你得亲自询问马利瑞先生了
You'll have to ask Mr. Malloy yourself.
我想冒昧地问一下  就是
You know, not for nothing,  But...
他是什么样的  我是说
what's he like? I mean...
从有点疯到汉尼拔
on a scale of 1 to Hannibal Lecter,
我们要面对的是怎样一个人
what are we dealing with here?
我很抱歉  但医患保密协议
I'm sorry,  But doctor-patient privilege
不允许我们形容或描述病人的行为
prohibits us from characterizing or describing our patients' behavior.
不  没关系  我们理解
No, that's okay. We understand.
到了
Here we are.
我们来讲一下规定
Let's go over the rules.
请不要给他任何东西
Please don't hand him any objects
也不要收他的任何东西
or take anything from him.
别站得离玻璃太近
Don't stand too close to the glass.
如果你们需要任何帮助
And if you need any help,
就按一下身后墙上的红色按钮
just press the red button on the wall behind you.
好了  请在这里签字
Okay, now please just sign here
以示你们明白了规定
acknowledging that you understand the rules.
我感觉就像签字把命卖了一样
I feel like I'm signing my life away.
但愿不会吧
Well, let's hope not.
谢谢
Thank you.
请  坐吧  很少有人会来探望我
Please... have a seat. I so rarely receive visitors.
但最近就有个人来探望过你
But you have received a visitor recently.
瓦尔·巴特勒  她为什么来找你
Val Butler. Why was she here?
甜美的好姑娘
Oh, sweet girl.
她跑来问我有没有寄东西给她
She came to ask me if I'd sent her something.
那你寄了吗
And did you?
我怎么能寄  我没办法寄任何东西给任何人
How could I? I can't send anything to anyone.
你可以让别人寄给她
You could've just gotten someone else to send it to her,
就像你可以派别人去杀了她一样
just like you could've gotten someone else to kill her.
我为什么要那么做
And why would I do such a thing?
为了延续你哥哥永生的神秘
To perpetuate the myth of your brother's immortality...
或者为他的死复仇
or to avenge his death.
我不是我哥哥的守护人  贝克特探长
I am not my brother's keeper, Detective Beckett.
我从来都不是  我没有他那种杀人的冲动
I never was, and I don't share his murderous impulses.
但你却仍然被关在这里
Yet, you're still in here.
暂时而已
For now.
但等到我的上诉结果出来  谁知道呢
But when my appeal comes through, who knows?
我们某天可能会在大街上相遇哦
We could all meet on the street one day.
真有那一天  我可能会穿过街去
On that day, I might cross the street.
我不会伤害任何人  从来不会
I'm no danger to anyone. I never was.
我为什么要参与谋杀案  毁了自己的上诉呢
So why would I jeopardize my appeal by being party to a murder?
因为你很清楚你可以脱罪
Because you knew you could get away with it.
你被关起来了
You're locked up.
你拥有完美的不在场证明
You have the perfect alibi.
我拥有完美的不在场证明  因为我是无辜的
I have the perfect alibi because I'm innocent.
我没有电视或网络
I don't have TV or internet access.
我没有发送或接收邮件
I don't send or receive mail.
我唯一和外界的接触就是访客
The only personal contact I have is through visitors,
瓦尔是我多年来最后一个访客
And Val is the last one I've had in years.
我能派谁去杀死她
So who could I have sent to dispatch her
或其他目击证人啊
or the other witness?
我们从没提过
Uh, well, we never actually
其他目击证人被杀
said anything about the other witness being killed.
那么  你是怎么知道这事的
So... how would you know anything about that?
我觉得你们该走了
I think it's time for you to go.
我没什么好说的了
I have nothing more to say.
听着  他已经坦白一切了
Look, he told us everything.
他不小心说漏嘴证明
That slipup proves that
他一直在跟某人交流关于那些凶案的信息
he's been talking with someone about those murders.
他还有一种方式可以知道那些信息
There is one other way he could've gotten that information.
他可能跟他哥哥交流过
He could be talking to his brother.
卡塞尔  他肯定是跟外面的人谈过
Castle, he was talking with someone on the outside.
他不可能和死人交流
He hasn't been communing with the dead.
我们可不敢完全确定  而且
Well, we can't be sure, and...
我们没有时间了
We're running out of time.
我会把我遗愿清单上的第27条划掉
So I'm gonna scratch off number 27 on my bucket list.
你记得你家餐桌上的
You remember that, uh, blue porcelain vase
那个蓝色瓷花瓶吗
you had on your dining room table?
当然  就是被风卷进来摔碎的那个
Yeah, the one that the wind blew over.
是啊  关于那个
Yeah, about that.
我当时在客厅打网球游戏
I was playing wii tennis in the living room,
-你打碎了我的瓷瓶  -花瓶
- You broke my vase? - Vase.
-说瓷瓶也可以啦  -你知道吗
- Vase is acceptable, too. - You know what?
你可以不用担心那些鬼魂缠上你了
You can stop worrying about the spirits getting to you,
因为我有可能会亲手杀了你
because I just might kill you myself.
不是吧你  要在我们生命的最后一天吵架吗
Seriously, you want to spend Our last day on earth fighting?
莱恩
Ryan.
你去弄张传票  查看那所精神病院的记录
Hey, we need you to subpoena records from the asylum.
看看里奥普通过电话或邮件跟谁联系过
See who Leopold was in contact with by phone or over e-mail.
好的  但是  我想告诉你
Yeah, sure, but just so you know,
案子有了点新进展
there's been a development.
你什么意思  什么新进展
What do you mean? What kind of a development?
我们在查马利瑞家族的信息时
Well, while looking into the Malloys,
在一份警方报告中发现了奈杰尔的名字
Nigel's name came up on a police report.
什么报告
What kind of a report?
报告上声称他几天前失踪了
He was, um... reported missing a few days ago.
失踪  那家伙已经死了超过3年了
Missing? The guy has been dead for over three years.
关于那一点
Yeah, about that...
奈杰尔死后所葬入墓地的看守人
the groundskeeper at the cemetery where Nigel is buried
注意到他的坟墓被侵扰过
noticed that his plot has been disturbed.
你是说被挖了吗
As in "dug up"?
不仅是被挖了
Well, not just dug up.
尸体失踪
奈杰尔·马利瑞的尸体失踪了
Nigel Malloy's body has disappeared.
那不是消失了
It hasn't disappeared.
他是死而复生了
He's risen from the grave.
臭名昭著的连环杀手尸体被盗
我们来听听
All right. Let's hear it.
听什么
Hear what?
你来解释一下这个
Your explanation for this.
如果说有什么我可以永远信赖
If there's one thing I can always count on,
那就是你和你的推理能力  所以嘛
It's you and your logic so...
你要我解释已故连环杀手的尸体怎么失踪了
You want me to explain the dead serial killer's missing body?
我不知道怎么回事
I don't know what happened here
暂时不知道
yet.
我擦  这也行
That's it? That's all you've got?
但我肯定这案子和奈杰尔·马利瑞复活
But I can assure you that it has nothing to do
没有一点关系
with Nigel Malloy rising from the dead.
是他弟弟
It's his brother.
里奥普·马利瑞才是幕后黑手
Leopold Malloy is behind all of this.
看来里奥普跟这案子没关系
It doesn't look like Leopold has anything to do with this.
不能吧
No,that can't be right.
这家伙是疯子  可是在一件事上他是对的
Look,the guy's crazy, But he was right about one thing.
他没有电话  电子邮箱  只有瓦尔拜访过他
He has no phone,no e-mail,and no visitors besides Val.
肯定有办法证明里奥普是幕后黑手
There's gotta be some way of proving that Leopold's behind all this.
我不知道他是怎么做到的
I can't tell you how he did it,
但我知道下一个被害人是谁
but I can tell you who's next.
我查了马利瑞案的法庭记录
I checked into the court documents on the Malloy trial.
发现了些规律  杰森是第一个证人
I noticed a pattern. Jason was the first person to testify,
而他是第一个被害人
and he was also the first one to die.
第二天被害的瓦尔  是第二个证人
A day later, Val, the second person who testified, was killed.
好  所以他们是按出庭作证的顺序被害的
Okay, so they're being killed in order of their testimonies.
谁是第三个
Who's lucky number three?
马克·海勒  我找了他女友
Uh, Mark Heller. I talked to his girlfriend.
他三天前收到了光盘
He received a disc three days ago.
也就是说他今晚午夜会死  还有四小时
That means he's due to die tonight at midnight. That's in four hours.
那马克·海勒现在在哪
And where's Mark Heller now?
不知道
That's the problem.
他看完视频后吓傻了
He watched the video and he freaked out.
他离开了家  没人知道去哪儿
He left the house. Nobody knows where he went.
我知道  海勒的消费记录显示
I might. Heller's financials show that
他昨天在金斯敦市外的商店买了东西
he bought groceries at a store outside Kingston yesterday.
他们家在那儿有间小屋
His family owns a Cabin up there.
估计他就躲在那儿
That's probably where he's holed up.
好  埃斯波西托  你继续里奥普
Okay, Esposito you keep digging into Leopold.
莱恩  找出其他证人
Ryan... find the other witnesses.
确保他们安全
Make sure they're safe.
我和卡塞尔去金斯敦找海勒
Castle and I will head off to Kingston and see if we can get Heller.
我们要去那个偏僻森林里的小屋吗
Uh, we're going to a cabin in the woods in the middle of nowhere?
对  怎么了
Yeah. So?
这就像是恐怖片里女学生去查看
So it's like the co-ed checking out the strange noise in the basement
地下室的怪声  这就是惹鬼上身啊
in a slasher pic. It's a recipe for disaster.
这又不是演恐怖电影  我们是调查凶案
It's not a slasher flick. It's a murder investigation.
我要去那小屋  你跟不跟去
And I'm going up to that cabin. So you coming or what?
我不能让你一个人去
Well, I can't let you go alone.
但我得先准备准备
But I need to make a stop first.
我带了香火  符咒  照妖镜
Okay, so I've got incense, palaspas, bagua mirror.
全套的驱鬼利器  鬼挡杀鬼  佛挡杀佛
This is a veritable war chest for fighting evil spirits.
-那是圣水吗  -对
- Is that holy water? - Yeah.
你从哪儿弄来的
Where'd you get that from?
两年前  一个教士开光了送我的
A priest blessed this for me two years ago.
你就一直留着吗
And you just keep it around?
我知道总会用得着的
Knew it would come in handy one day.
好  你想要哪样武器
Now... What weapon do you want?
我有枪就行了
I think I'll be fine with my gun.
对于我的看法
There's not just one... tiny part of you
你就真的一点也不信吗
that wonders if I might be right?
-喂  贝克特  -莱恩
- Hey, Beckett. - Ryan?
喂  贝克特
Hey, Beckett?
莱恩  我们这儿信号不好
Ryan, wh-- I think we're in a bad area.
我听不清你说话
I'm having a hard time hearing you.
好的  那我长话短说
Okay, then I'll make it quick.
我刚找到最后一个证人
I just finished with the last of the remaining witnesses.
他们都没收到光盘
None of them got a disc.
所以凶手只想杀前三个证人
So the killer only targeted the first three witnesses.
有可能是这样  也有可能只是还没动手
Well, either that or he hasn't gotten around to the others yet.
哥们  我们听不见了
Dude, you're breaking up.
先别挂
Uh, uh, hang on.
看看这个
Yo, check this out.
看来瓦尔  杰森和马克·海勒还有别的共同点
Looks like Val, Jason, and Mark Heller had something else in common.
喂  贝克特  我们漏了些事
Hey, Beckett. We missed something.
事情不如我们所料  而是另有乾坤
I-it's not what we think. There's someone else.
贝克特  贝克特
Beckett? Beckett.
联系不上他了  我完全没信号
I can't get him back. I don't have any reception.
那是海勒的车  他在这儿
There's Heller's car. He's here.
嗯  我也完全没信号
Yeah, I haven't got any bars either.
这地方的确比较偏僻
Yeah, well, we are in the middle of nowhere.
还能更糟吗
Can this get any worse?
一个已故连环杀手离奇失踪
A dead serial killer has gone missing,
我俩都看了诅咒光盘
we've both seen a cursed disc,
身在阴森的林中小屋  手机又没信号
we're at a cabin in the woods with no cell phone reception--
傻子都知道这故事会怎么发展
I don't need Wes Craven to tell me how this ends.
卡塞尔  你得这么想
Well, think about it this way, Castle.
在所有恐怖电影里
In all of those horror movies,
-总有人能活下来  -是啊  "有人"而已
- someone survives. - Yeah, someone.
我俩中的一人
One of us.
我们中的一人天生风趣幽默
And the other one is cursed with being charming and funny.
用不着我来告诉你
I don't think I need to tell you
那些搞笑的角色都是什么下场
what kind of chances the comic relief guy has.
马克·海勒
Mark Heller.
Mark Heller?
哎呀妈呀
Jeez.
这装饰太吓人了
Can't say I'm a fan of the decor.
我也不喜欢  可我们是来
Yeah, well, neither am I, but we're just here to--
你们要是不走  那就死定了
Unless you leave, you're gonna die.
海勒先生  我是贝克特探长  纽约警局的
Mr Heller, I'm Detective Beckett. NYPD.
那你不介意出示你的证件吧
Well, then you won't mind showing me I.D.
我必须保持警惕
I can't be too cautious,
马利瑞案的证人都离奇身亡
Not with Malloy witnesses dropping like flies.
我们知道光盘的事
Look, we know about the disc.
我们是来带你回去的  以便保护你
We're here to take you to the precinct, where we can protect you.
你们保护不了我  他回来了
You can't protect me. He's back.
马克  按照推断  你还有两分钟就...
Look, Mark, if the pattern holds, you got two minutes before...
你懂的  所以我们上车再说吧
you know, so let's talk about this in the car.
你知道吗  跟马利瑞待在同一个审判室
You know, just being in the same courtroom as Malloy
就足以让大老爷们尿裤子了
was enough to make a grown man wet himself.
那个疯子成天嚷嚷些装神弄鬼的
Psycho yammering about death and rebirth and all that hoo-ha.
我们可以上车了聊
Okay, hoo-ha we could be talking about--
其实我  瓦尔和杰森
You know, neither me nor Val nor Jason
都不想指证他和其他同伙
wanted to testify against him or the other guy.
什么其他同伙
What do you mean,the other guy?
你是说里奥普吗
Are you talking about Leopold?
-老天爷  -时辰到
- Oh, god. - Time's up.
它来了
It's here.
你觉得它会让我俩再活一天吗
Do you think it'll matter that we still have a day left
还是干脆一次把我们仨都干掉
or will I be like a three birds with one stone thing?
你家电闸在哪儿
Where are your circuit breakers?
-在工具房外  -好
- Outside by the toolshed. - Okay.
有人在外面
Someone's out there.
当真吗  它长啥样
Seriously? What's it like?
是个幽灵吗  脸色惨白吗  怒火中烧吗
Is it, uh, ghastly, pale, pissed?
我看不清他的脸
I can't get a good look at his face.
你家有后门吗
Do you have a back door?
有有  穿过厨房就是
Yeah, yeah. Through the kitchen.
卡塞尔  你守着马克
Okay, Castle, you keep an eye on Mark.
我出去看看
I'm gonna head out back,
我从后面迂回过去  给他个突然袭击
Double around, see if I can surprise him.
什么  等一下  我们分头行动
What? Wait. We're splitting up?
是的
Yeah.
纽约警察  站在那儿别动
NYPD. Hold it right there.
他就不能放过我们吗
Why can't he just leave us alone?
我们已经很倒霉了
We suffered so much already.
内疚已经快把我们三个折磨死了
The guilt nearly killed the three of us.
你们把那个连环杀手定了罪
Why would you have guilt
为什么要感到内疚呢
about getting a serial killer convicted?
因为那不是事情的全部
Because that's not the whole story.
我们的手上也沾有鲜血
We all have blood on our hands.
鲜血  什么鲜血
Blood? What blood?
马克  跟我说说  我需要知道
Mark, talk to me. I need to know.
你说的鲜血是什么意思
What blood is on your hands?
有关系吗
What does it matter?
他回来找我们算账了  我们都得死
He's come back for us. We're all gonna die.
如果是因为你做错了什么的话
It matters because if you did something wrong,
这可能就是我们活着出去的关键
it could be the key to getting out of this alive.
放开我  放开我
Get off of me! Let me go!
是你  里奥普的护士
You? Leopold's nurse.
-里奥普  是你干的  -不
- Leopold. It was you. - No.
不  不是
No. No.
-是你帮他杀人的  -不  不是的
- You're the one that's killing for him. - No,no.
你不明白
You don't understand.
怪不得他能接近那些证人  他是利用你
That's how he got to the witnesses. He was using you.
你搞错了
You don't get it.
我不是来这杀海勒的  我是来救他的
I'm not here to kill Heller. I'm here to save him.
你在说些什么啊
What are you even talking about?
-这就是里奥普派我来的原因  -退后
- That's why Leopold sent me. - Step back.
-好的  好的  -退后
- Okay.Okay. All right. - Step back.
他知道别人会以为他是凶手
He knew that people would think that he was behind the murders,
那样的话他就永远无法离开精神病院
And then he wouldn't be able to get out of the asylum.
我爱他  我只是想帮他
I love him. I was just trying to protect him.
我们知道我们必须得阻止这些谋杀
We knew we had to stop the murders.
不是我们干的  我发誓
It--it's not us. I swear.
如果不是你们  那会是谁
If it's not you, then who is it?
我不知道
I don't know,
但我去了奈杰尔的坟墓想确认一下
but I went to Nigel's grave just to be sure.
我把坟墓挖开了  他不见了
I dug it up. He was gone.
不  死人不会杀人
No. Evil spirits don't kill.
活人才会
People do.
在奈杰尔之前  警察还逮捕了别人
Before Nigel, The police arrested someone else--
大卫·克里尔
David Collier.
那人有精神病史
Guy had a history of mental illness.
我  瓦尔和杰森把他指认出来了
Me, Val, and Jason had to pick him out of a lineup.
我们都不确定  但是警察  他们
None of us were sure. But the police, they...
他们迫使你们不得不说是克里尔干的
They pressured you into saying it was Collier.
他后来怎样了
What happened to him?
他承受不了那些指控  还有人们的议论
He couldn't take it-- the accusations, what people were saying.
他把牢房里的灯打碎了
He smashed a lightbulb in his cell
然后触电自杀了
and he used the wire to electrocute himself.
这么说他死了
So his heart stopped.
他什么时候死的  马克  准确时间
When did he die? Mark, exactly when did he die?
他入狱后第三天的午夜
At midnight, third night he was in prison.
"你看见了  三天后的午夜你就会死"
"You saw. Midnight third day, you die. "
跟奈杰尔没关系  是跟克里尔有关
This isn't about Nigel. It's about Collier.
马克  你得想想
Mark, you gotta think.
他有没有什么朋友或者家人
Did he have any friends, any relatives?
是的  他有一个女儿  阿曼达
Yeah, he had a daughter. Amanda.
瓦尔的室友叫阿曼达
Val's roommate's name is Amanda.
有人来了
Someone's here.
你三天的时间到了  马克
Your three days are up, Mark.
我父亲也同样承受了三天的恐惧
The same three days of fear my father had.
站住  别动
Stop... Right there.
我看不见了
Right in my eyes!
枪  我看不见  她在哪
The gun! I can't see. Where is she?
这是为我父亲报仇
This is for my father.
卡塞尔
Castle!
看见了吧
See?
我就说这瓶圣水会派上用场
Told you this holy water would come in handy.
根据阿曼达的心理评估记录
So according to Amanda's psych records,
她一年前经受了一次精神创伤
she suffered a mental break about a year ago.
她一定是从那时开始准备复仇的
That must be when she started fixating on revenge.
计划着要惩罚所有错误指认了他父亲的人
Plannign to punish all those who wrongly I.D.'ed her dad.
她一定是拼命讨好瓦尔
You know, she must have cozied up to Val
从而找到了杰森和马克
to find out where Jason and Mark were.
还有  她用这个把他们撂倒了
And... she used this to knock them out.
杯子
The mug?
不  是电击枪  改造过了
No, the taser. It's a modified taser.
它能释放出令人眩晕的光线和加大的电压
It emits a disorienting light and amplified voltage.
足以使心脏停止跳动的电压
Enough voltage to stop a heart.
而且还能使面部肌肉收缩
And make the facial muscles contract.
我想阿曼达是想要那些对他父亲的死
I guess Amanda wanted the people responsible For her father's death
负有责任的人承受和他父亲一样的痛苦
to suffer the same way he did.
也就是三天的恐惧
So three days of fear
最后在黑暗中  心脏停跳而死去
capped up with a dark, heart-stopping death.
但是她是怎么造成停电的呢
Yeah, but how did she get the power to go out?
她用的这个
She used this.
她把这个连在小屋的断路器上
She attached it to the cabin's circuit breaker.
它释放出的磁荷
It emits a magnetic charge
影响了电路系统
that interferes with the system.
所以说  所有的事都有合乎逻辑的解释
So... I guess that there is a logical explanation for everything.
说不好  奈杰尔的事怎么说
Oh,I don't know. What about Nigel?
他的尸体怎么会从坟墓里不见了呢
How did his body go missing from his grave?
我来回答吧
I can answer that.
原来他从没被下葬
Turns out he was never buried.
他的尸体在他死后不久就从太平间消失了
His body disappeared from the morgue shortly after his death.
警察不想让别人知道
The police didn't want to make it known,
所以就埋了一个空棺材
So they buried an empty coffin.
但奇怪的是  他的尸体一直没被找到
But here's the odd thing-- his body was never found.
这么说  他可能仍然在
So... he could still be out there...
某个地方
somewhere.
这杯庆祝我们出色地完成了任务
Okay,so... here's to a job well done.
你现在终于可以扔掉你的这份
And now you can finally get rid of this bucket... list
遗愿清单了
of yours.
怎么这个表情
What's that look for?
"跟凯特在一起"
"Be with Kate"?
排在第一个  你什么时候写的
That's your number one? When did you write this?
差不多三年前吧
What, like three years ago?
现在我可以把这条划去了
I can cross that one off.
抱歉  还有一分钟才到午夜
Sorry. Still one minute till midnight.
你没搞错吧  卡塞尔
Are you serious, Castle?
没有  我认真的  我可不想冒险
Yes, I'm serious. I'm not taking any chances.
我真的很想错过这个死期
This is one deadline I want to miss.
你说的对
You know, you're right.
要是我们俩有什么三长两短真的很遗憾
It would be a shame if something happened to us
因为我的遗愿清单上也有一件
because there's one thing on my bucket list
我很想完成的事
that I would like to accomplish.
而且这事还跟我玩弄冰块
And it involves a little trick that I do...
有关
with ice.
你看  就冲这事儿我们也得活着
See, now that definitely sounds worth living for.
卡塞尔  冰块可要化了哦
Hey, Castle... the ice is melting.
好的  就  倒计时
Okay, ju--I just-- In...
三  二
three, two...